evening ladies and gentlemen a very warm
welcome to ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q4 and fy23
earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav dasgupta MD and CEO
of the company Mr gopal balachandran CFO
and cro Mr Sanjeev mantri executive
director and Mr alok Agarwal executive
director
please note that any statements or
comments made into race call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future and more risk and
uncertainties which could cause the
results to differ materially from the
current views bring expressed
as a reminder all R7 lines will be in
the listen only mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes
need assistance during this conference
call please signal an operator by
pressing start and 0 on your Touchstone
phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
I now hand the conference over Mr
bhargav dasgupta MD and CEO ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited thank
you and over to you sir
thank you anirov and good evening to
each one of you thank you for joining
the earnings conference call of Isis
Lombard General Insurance company for Q4
and the F5 2023 I will give you a view
of brief overview of the industry Trends
and developments that we have witnessed
in the past few months post this RCA
phone Mr gopal balachandran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and your ended March
31st 2023.
is showing signs of resilience while the
global economic uncertain remains
eligible domestically all the leading
indicators are pointing towards
sustained momentum in the economic
activity however Persistence of elevated
inflation in advanced economies
tightening Financial conditions and
ongoing geopolitical tensions may impact
domestic Force going forward
as for data published by CM the new
vehicle sales continues deliver growth
year on year for Private Car however the
pendant demand
seems to have settled commercial vehicle
segments continue to deliver robust
growths while the two wheeler segment in
terms of volumes is still below the
pre-pandemic level
health insurance continued that the
river over score commercial lines
witness growth in line with the current
market environment the overall growth of
the industry was highest in the last
five years we remain optimistic with the
industry will continue to grow given the
favorable regulatory changes low
penetration and positive customers
sentiments
speaking of the performance the GI
industry delivered a gdpi growth of 16.4
percent for FY 2823 at the same time the
underwriting performance remained weak
with the combined ratio of the industry
at 116.2 for nine months of this year as
against hundred nineteen point two for
nine months fi 2022
for motor business the combined ratio
for the industry was 123.5 for half year
of this year which improved to 8 118.9
for Q3 f523 as for public disclosures
while there will be gradual signs of
improvement in the motorcycle the
combined ratio remains higher than FY 22
levels which was at 115.6
The Authority in The Current financial
year introduced various reforms seeking
to expand the market and increase the
penetration of insurance products during
this quarter The Authority notified
extensive management and payment of
commission regulations proposing an
aggregate limit at a company level with
essence of 1st April 2023
moving to the business impact for us
during the quarters the company grew by
6.7 percent
including crop and and one one-off
transaction in
the segment become the coming grew by
12.6 percent as against the industry
growth X crop of 17.95 coming to the
growth of key segments
there are just slight disturbance coming
from the line
participants
uh yes and now it's better okay uh so
I'll just repeat uh the last line that I
spoke uh coming to the growth of the key
segments during this quarter in the
commercial lines we experienced romance
growth driven by growth of 15.9 percent
of the SMA segment
accredited market share across segments
such as engineering liability and
maintenance market share in the fire
segment
in addition to the above another
development in the commercial line
segment was the discontinuance of IRB
rates as minimum rates in the fire
reinsurance treaties due to a regulatory
directive
also the impact of global hardening on
reinsurance terms especially on natural
catastrophic catastrophic protection was
experienced by the insurance during
April 1 renewals we believe that
although this may create short-term
disruption in the long term this is
expected to be positive and bring in
underwriting discipline at the same time
for players like us who have capital
scale we should benefit from this
in motor we debut by 11.5 percent
excluding the one-off transaction the
growth was muted at 0.6 percent as
against the industry growth of 13.1
percent
we continue to focus on profitable sub
segments using historical granular data
and rebalanced a portfolio result in a
CV mix at 22.3 percent and two wheeler
mixed at 27.8 for f by 2823 similar to
the previous year the overall health
segment continued to be the fastest
growing segment of the industry during
the quarter we grew at 31.1 percent
which was higher than the industry
growth of 29.7
in group health the employer employee
segment the change in underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards companies which
have better underwriting and service
capabilities
resulting in a group health segment to
grow by 35.7 during the quarter and 43.9
percent for the year
as a result of a continued investment in
retail Health distribution we have
outgrown the industry for Q4 fi 2023
with the growth of 19.4 percent and in
the month of March with a growth of 27
percent this was driven by business
source through retail health agency
vertical which grew at 30.9 further in
the month of February we undertook a
price increase in our retail Health
Indemnity renewal book at approximately
about 19 percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs I'll take care of has
passed 4.6 million user downloads till
date the incremental download for the
quarter was close to 1 million
for Q4 of fi23 water and water growth of
Premium Source through this app was 58.4
percent which is over the previous
quarter of Q3 of FY 23 thus contributing
55.1 crore to gdpi for Q3 of f523 this
number was
347.9 million or 34.7 crore for Q2 it
was 27.4 code and for q1 it was
centralized
our bank insurance and key relationship
groups grew at 25.7 this quarter within
this ICC Bank distribution grew at 14.2
percent and the non-icc Bank
distribution grew at 32.2 percent
post pandemic the recovering credit
growth along with increasing wallet
share in distribution Partners acquired
through the demeriture has been the key
growth driver
our business source through a digital
wanting grew 19.4 percent overall our
digital Focus has enabled us to increase
our digital revenues which includes the
I'll take care of to 3.14 billion which
accounts for 6.3 percent of our overall
gdpa for the quarter if we remain on
track and are focused on growth levers
such as Innovation digital advancements
launching new products strengthening our
distribution engine rationalizing cost
while scaling about different lines of
business I will now request gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the Recently concluded quarter
thanks my girlfriend uh good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the company for quarter
four and FY 2023 we have uploaded the
results presentation on our website you
can access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
cross direct premium income of the
company was rupees 210.25 billion in FY
2023 as against rupees 179.77 billion in
fy22 a growth of 17 against the industry
growth of 16.4 percent
growth was primarily driven by growth in
the preferred segments the overall gdpa
of our Property and Casualty segment
grew by 18.9 at rupees 59.73 billion and
f523 has against rupees 50.24 million
and fy22
on the retail side of the business GDP
of the motor segment was at rupees 85.82
billion in fy23 as against rupees 82.8
billion up by 22 registering a growth of
3.7 percent
excluding the one-off transaction that
Bargo referred to the growth was at 6.9
percent
our agents including the point of sale
distribution count was around 1 lakh 13
000 as on March 31 2023 a up from one
lakh 6119 as on December 31 2022. the
advanced premium was rupees 32.17
billion as at 131 2023 as against rupees
32.79 billion as at December 31 2022
resultantly combined ratio was 104 4.5
percent for the full year as against
108.8 in FY 22. combined ratio for the
quarter was on 104.2 percent this year
as against 103.2 percent in quarter for
fy22 our investment assets Rose to
rupees 431.8 billion at March 31 2023 up
from RS 414.51 billion at December 31
2022 our investment leverage debt of
borrowings was 4.15 times
at Mass 31 2023 as against 4.16 at
December 31 2022. investment income for
the whole year was rupees 29.77 billion
as against rupees 30 billion in FY 2022
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to 8.17 billion in Q4 fy23 as
against rupees 7.06 billion Q4 F5 2022
our capital gains net of impairment on
uh investment assets stood at rupees
4.53 billion in FY 2023 as compared to
rupees 7.38 billion in fy22
23 was at rupees 1.59 billion as
compared to rupees 1.36 billion in
quarter four FY 22. our profit before
tax blew by 25.5 at rupees 21.13 billion
in f523 as against rupees 16.84 billion
in FY 2022 whereas PBT grew by 39.5 at
rupees 5.73 billion Q4 fy23 as against
rupees 4.1 billion in Q4 F5 22.
consequently profit after tax grew by 36
percent at rupees 17.29 billion fy23 as
against rupees 12.71 billion in fy22
whereas profit after tax
grew by 39.8 percent at rupees 4.37
billion Q4 fy23 up from rupees 3.13
billion in Q4 f522 but includes the
reversal of tax provision of rupees 1.28
billion in Q2 F5 2023 the board of
directors of the company has proposed a
final dividend of rupees 5.5 per share
for fy23 the payment is however subject
to approval of shareholders in their
swing and original meeting of the
company the overall dividend for FY 2023
including the proposed final dividend is
rupees 10 per share last year it was 9
rupees per share written on average
Equity was 17.7 in fy23 as it is 14.7
percent in FY 22. the return on average
equity for the quarter four FY 23 was
17.2 percent as against 14 in Q4 f522
so always the ratio was 2.5 times at
Mass 31 2023 as against 2.45 times at
December 31 2022 continues to be higher
than the regulatory minimum of 1.5 times
as I conclude I would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policyholders at at all times I would
like to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and now we will be happy
to take any questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question Q symbols
participants you may press star in one
to ask a question
the first question is from
bnk Securities please go ahead
in the recent conversations you have
mentioned that there have been some you
know small but positive development on
the pricing side in uh motor OD uh but
despite that I think what we are seeing
uh you know in your numbers is that
there has been uh the growth in the
motor premium so just wanted to
understand sir uh what is playing out
there and what has resulted is this a
high base effect or anything else that
we need to understand to factor in this
these groups that we have seen in the
modern book and also sir generally if
you can highlight the reason for the
mobility loss ratio being higher this
quarter because I checked the reserve
cycles and there seems to be
you scored
so the first one sworn up on the motor
won't damage
growth numbers I think in line with what
we have been talking about uh why we
continue to be a bit cautious given the
fact that the competitive intensity on
motor stays elevated having said that
you were right we did talk about maybe
some bit of easing in pricing that one
had expected uh to kind of play through
on the motor segment which is why when
you look at the industry combined ratios
for the half years industry combined was
that roughly about 124 if you look at
that number for quarter three that
number was about 118 so clearly I think
there seems to be some signs of a bit of
easing in so far as the industry
participants are concerned
I think if you recollect what we had
said was
obviously we continue to write the motor
segment through a combination of both
new as well as the relatively older
segment and as we have been explaining
we have been also looking at segments
which are slightly older which typically
comes with a slightly higher loss
experience and the relative cost of
acquisition for that particular segment
is relatively lower so fans from an Roe
perspective it made a lot of sense for
us to look at writing that part of the
business and hence to that extent you
would possibly see maybe the Los ratios
slightly elevated
having said that I think what we would
always urge is to not look at maybe any
numbers on a quarter on quarter basis
but rather look at it more on a full
year basis in terms of the opportunity
so that's one
on motor third party loss ratios again
we will continue to make the same stance
which is to say that in a given quarter
there are a lot of factors that
influence the loss experience and
therefore in so far as if you ask us
whether there has been any change in our
reserving philosophy or approach there
has been no change in the reserving
philosophy or approach and motor TP
being unlike some of the other segments
which are short tail in terms of loss
development as we know it's a relatively
long tale of planes and there again I
think we would again urge all of you to
look at numbers more on a full year
basis and if you look at on a full year
basis the motor third party loss ratio
for the current year stands at 72
percent so that's a better reflection of
the loss experience as compared to
looking at the numbers on a quadrant
quarter basis just to add one more point
to what gopal said uh when you compare
yui numbers last year Q4 for us was a
very big quarter for uh in motor
business
but otherwise in terms of pushing price
increases that we are actually taking we
pushed to some price increases we will
see whether others follow
okay uh got it sir also uh I mean in
terms of the overall cost structures are
I mean ideally I understand that Q4 is
generally a retail heavy quarter and
hence our commission outgo uh is
generally much higher but this time the
net commission ratio is somewhere around
two percent two to two point two percent
and no number so is there any impact of
the one-off transaction in this if you
could highlight the reason and also uh
the one-off transaction if I were to
triangulate the number somewhere in the
pnl how how should I you know look look
for it
so attrition so far as
the net commission is concerned I think
there is some there is definitely
nothing which is more one-off uh we
obviously see cyclicality in some of the
outcomes when you see on a quadrant
quarter performance particularly for
example or some of the uh commercial
line portfolios we get to see the
experience of how good or bad the
hopefully outcome has been that gets
demonstrated at the end of financial
year particularly in quarter four and
hence to that extent you will possibly
be able to see some element of maybe
profit commission that typically gets
recognized in Q4
that's it there's nothing which is like
one off and in general as we have been
talking about on the commercial line our
portfolio experience has been in that
sense profitable and therefore the terms
of commissions that we get from the
reinsurers is what has possibly resulted
in maybe the net commission ratio
reflecting a different number
but otherwise there is no one-off in so
far as this particular recognition is
concerned
thank you sorry to interrupt you I'll
request to join the queue again for a
follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
Avinash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead
yeah hi uh good evening uh two questions
our first is more on the regulatory side
where regulator has sort of uh bring in
of I would say awake Clause saying that
benefit of a direct distribution to be
passed on to the uh policyholders now
here my question is that is the
regulator sort of a saying uh to you or
the industry that okay you have to have
a kind of a direct version of the same
policy or if not I mean I'm saying that
simply that okay what if a health policy
a retail policy a customer coming for
Renewal now are you supposed to pass on
that if the customer is willing to pay
to your branch and your portal directly
are you willing or are you required now
to pass on the this deep commission
difference I mean I am talking for
anybody I mean there is definitely no
almost no cost in terms of direct I can
understand the cost on the new issue but
when a customer is coming for the
renewal directly for health I mean
virtually there is no distribution costs
involved so I mean are you going to pass
on are you required that's number one
and second uh on the you know extensive
management side I mean of course the new
regulation has come but even for the
existing regulation perspective I mean
for your scale the 31 kind of a reported
expensive management it looks or I mean
there's something I mean the operating
leverage uh is kind of a bit evasive and
to add to that if I see the p l there is
some close to 900 support crores or like
you know close to four percent of your
uh gross premium that is being charged
with say a holder's account whereas the
ratio says 31 percent so why is I mean
uh at least on the ratio it does not
appear as if you have breached uh
expense of management by that kind of
amount so what the sort of a connection
I am missing here do you have two
questions thank you
Google will take the second question let
me answer the first
I think the direction that the regulator
is taking is
making the regulation more principle
based and leaving in independent
companies with lot more flexibility to
manage their business in the way they
think appropriate
everything that you're that they're
doing at least our read of the matter is
there giving insurance companies a bit
more Choice than what we had in the past
so even when it comes to the fact that
you can give a lower commission that is
also a choice given which in the past we
not explicitly given
as a company we still have been giving a
lower price in the online policies by
two and a half to five percent so that's
the practice that we've been been doing
and we will continue to do that coming
to what will happen because of this I
think you know it's just too early to
comment on how Market would would adjust
to these changes uh but as I said my
sense is that it is uh giving a lot more
flexibility to us and a different
companies will plan out what they want
to do with these flexibilities
you know do remember that the in certain
products the agent even if let's say
customer reviews online sometimes agents
do play a role in recommending that and
driving that behavior
um may not be true for everything but a
lot of times it is that is how it is but
as I said more importantly it's a choice
given to insurance companies you plan
their business strategy
Avinash on the second point
I think the number what you're saying of
31.4 percent is Basis uh for quarter
four based on regulatory stipulated way
of computing the expensive management
ratio so there if you see the
denominator as what is being put out on
the footnotes it's based on the gross
direct premium income
having said that the threshold on the
expense of management works on the basis
of gross return premium so when you kind
of compute the numbers on the basis of
gross return premium the 31.4 percent
will stand
revised to let's say 29.5 which is
within the threshold of compliance in so
far as the limits on expensive
management is concerned the same number
on a full year basis what you are seeing
of 29.6 which is again based on gross
direct premium income in line with the
requirement of the regulation which is
on growth written premium that number
will be looking like 29 which is again
within the threshold on uh limits that
has been laid down by expensive
management
so that's one figure second point on
there seems to be an amount of let's say
close to about 900 crores which is
reflected as a part of the p l uh
disclosures uh what the regulator is
also under the earlier regime which is
valid until March 23 and also stipulated
one compliance system at an aggregate
level which is what I explained very
well within the limits on laid down with
the regulation two as you know they are
also laid down limits for individual
lines of businesses and in case if there
are any line of businesses where
possibly the limits on expenses slightly
elevated then to that extent from a
disclosure perspective so much of the
excess is required to be separately
disclosed as a part of the p l numbers
but when the computation of the combined
ratio happens it factors in for all the
operating expenses that we encourage the
company so it's more a disclosure that
is stipulated by the regulation as
compared to the fact that it is not a
case where at a company level we have
exceeded the limits on expensive
management we are well within the
threshold
thank you a quick follow-up I mean sorry
a different one on the reins inside if I
see there are three kind of a changes
happening one of course a global
hardening in the research Market the
second thing I see you know that kind of
a regulator nudging the primary ensure
that okay go ahead without any sort of a
reinsurance prescribed or flow rate that
was a kind of a practice in commercial
airlines of course that's the kind of a
second impact and thirdly with the new
um regulation coming on the gwp basis or
probably I mean the way some primary
companies or even regions companies
soliciting uh started reusable
businesses where commissions might be I
mean get a bit disturbed the kind of a
Resource Commission they would be paying
because now this I guess new um
regulation of 30 will be applicable on
all these three things that you know a
bit of dislocation commissions uh you
know the period of driven flow rates not
really mandatory rather uh you know is
just trying to choose and certainly the
global reason is Market hardening all
this net net how is going to sort of
impact the you know that yours or the
industry Behavior as far as the
commercial line or kind of a a heavily
resistance backline are concerned
so no you've that's a great Point
Avinash and we've been talking about the
fact that your commercial land that will
be a fair amount of uh change even in
the last quarter before these things
were explicitly clear we were talking
about the fact that some of these
changes would have impact of course we
couldn't anticipate the rate hardening
on the reinsurance side to that time but
that's now evident
so the
in certain markets has gone up by you
know 50 60 percent in our Market it's
also gone up by 45 to 60 for most
players in the market
uh that's an input cost to us largely we
uh the on the non-proportion set the
cost has gone up the commissions that
reinsurance give on the proportional
side has gone down so it's a it's a it's
a significant increase in cost the
second is as you like you said that
pricing is largely not mandated to be in
line with the burning cost of the
industry so individual companies can
charge whatever they want to
and hence there is a risk that the
pricing can a job
our senses and you know um of course is
there but at the end of the day finally
it's within you know overall combined
and me CEO has a very positive
development uh in the sense that uh you
know it's expected from the regulator
that companies will reduce their
expensive management even if their
bureaus are threshold and those above
the threshold have to bring it down to
30 within three years so that should
drive
positive behavior you know anticipation
so that um I don't see as a negative in
this sense
two perspective uh you know I think the
way we are seeing the market in the
first month
the or the second issue in terms of
rates coming
uh specifically one or two cases have
come down but on aggregate the rates
haven't come down as much as we would be
worried about it's come down a little
bit but nothing material uh our sense is
that you know usually is a big month uh
gives a sense of where the market is
headed and in future also we are not
anticipating a major drop in commercial
rates in the market simply because the
industry cannot afford to you know as
you rightly identified on one side the
cost has gone up and it's not as if the
combined ratio for the industry was very
healthy so I don't think the industry
has too much of a wherewithal to you
know reduce prices much in
you know cases that will happen but not
scale
the last one that I'll make is that you
know if you check certain companies go
very aggressive on the property side and
in effect end up burning their treaty uh
the regions Market which is hardening
that we are seeing and the attitude
hardening this is the rituals don't have
appetite to give a city capacity which
you can keep burning and that's what you
feel in the market this year right so if
that happens if any company does that
our senses in the next year they will
find it very difficult to get a proper
treaty capacity I think this is some
companies travel uh you know more will
struggle if that happens
writing we should tend to benefit
our experience or our estimate for the
year uh you know we've been giving a
guidance as a company that over the next
two years we want to bring it down to
102 we are not changing the Riders In
Spite of this uh cost increase on the
reinsurance side
thank you very much
the next question is from the line of
prayer Shane from Modi LA Los 1 please
go ahead
oh yeah hi good evening everyone uh two
questions from my side uh firstly could
you highlight as to when this one-off
transaction happened in February there
would be some income and which line item
does that income uh income sits in uh
secondly uh the easiest on seasonality
motor TP loss ratios because in past
three years we've seen Q4 being far more
elevated than Q3 uh and in one of the I
think if I connect well in one of the
fourth quarters you had mentioned that
this was that was because of adverse
judgments uh adverse judgments in that
case and thirdly uh we've seen a sharp a
good decline in terms of uh absolute
cause for advertisement and publicity
sales promotion employee remuneration
and that's you know recent decline in
terms of sequentially uh so what is the
kind of language that we should think
about the from your perspective of next
year
the praise on the one-off transaction
which we have been kind of explaining
that's something that has happened in
quarter four and uh this is in that
sense something that we did in line with
what let's say other Market participants
have been possibly doing it in the
current year or maybe in the earlier
years as well uh so hence to that extent
uh it's a commercially viable
transaction that we have kind of
undertaken and hence to that extent the
outcome of the transaction will be
reflected in the overall underwriting
result
uh when you look at the aggregate
numbers uh in so far as your motor third
party uh loss ratio trend line of
seasonality between quarter four there
is in that sense not any specific
seasonality that typically gets attached
so for example if you recollect two
years back which is in fy21 at that
point of time when we had possibly seen
elevated levels of motor third-party
losses loss ratios being higher so it
kind of talk to the market to say that
we did see at that point of Time
incrementally new Supreme Court
judgments that had come through in terms
of defining the basis on which
compensation will get paid to victims
object
and hence to that extent when we kind of
evaluated that particular book we
obviously wanted to make sure that we
did not know in which direction that
would take shape in so far as future
settlements are concerned but having
said that given that you always followed
a prudent approach to reserving we
obviously wanted to strengthen the
results at that point of time and hence
to that extent you would have possibly
seen maybe an elevated quarter four
motor third party loss number uh the
last year again is more a function
depending on how things have come back
in terms of normalcy because last two
years typically has been periods where
we have seen in different quarters uh
kovid experiences play out and ends to
that extent the scale of operations will
possibly also be a function of what kind
of loss experience that one exhibits and
thirdly as we keep saying one should
always look at particularly long tail
line of businesses experiences more on
ideally or longer years but definitely
not on a quarter on quarter basis you
should look at it look at more on annual
numbers as compared to let's say looking
at a quarter on quarter tank
the last point of yours I think as we
have kept saying uh we do kind of look
at productivity and efficiency in the
overall means of doing business and
hence is where we are kind of spoken
about what Virgo just mentioned where
clearly the direction that you want to
take is to bring down the overall
combined from the current levels of
closer to 104 that we have been
operating down to let's say 102 over the
next two years
and within that we are extremely focused
on looking at every element of cost
whether it is the cost of doing business
even any other
Investments that were kind of looking
through
so in that sense it is not that there is
any significant change we continue to
make investments in the health agency
platform that we have spoken about we
continue to stay invested in digital and
in line with our recent digital day that
we had which we kind of shared with all
of you we continue to stay invested in
the various technology transformation
projects as well so hence to that extent
that is how we should look at in terms
of the loss in terms of the expense
ratio trend line nothing specific that
is there is a one-off in so far as the
quarter four numbers is concerned
thank you
thank you very much
the next question is from the line of
sharia from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity sir I
have most of my questions are answered
so I have one doubt missing doubt that
the the reinsurance that gets added to
this gross direct premium
um and eventually becomes gross premium
written is high for sports quarters
seasonally or
um because even last year it was a
higher number this year again it's not
available
attached to it for example you would see
on the corporate side to be
significantly heavy in q1
heavy in Q3 you may see Q2 and Q3
seasonality attached to crop so
therefore different businesses exhibit
and maybe retail health for the matter
of fact to some extent I would say
attached to some seasonality in Q4 as
well so hence there are different lines
of businesses that exhibit seasonality
and as to that extent the reinsurance
inward could also be one of them but at
the end of the day whichever segment
that we are talking about we obviously
look at it from the ultimate lens of
profitable growth
all that I was referring to is different
segments of businesses could have
seasonality attached to it as an example
I am not saying in the context of
reinsurance inward even on the direct
side on retail Health you will possibly
see Q4 to be a slightly seasonally
higher quarter
uh reinsurance inward could be a mix of
business across different segments it
need not be necessarily only held
okay okay okay got it yeah that was my
only question
thank you
next question is from the line of nidesh
Jain from investec please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity there's
three questions firstly on the combined
ratio uh what is the impact of this
one-off transaction on our combined
ratio of 10 or 4.2 percent
uh secondly uh what is the health agency
gdpi in absolute terms uh for f523 and
Q4 fi 23
and lastly uh we have got access to HDFC
bank and access bank if you can share
how is the progress there what is the
business which we have been able to
Source from these channels uh in f523 or
Q45 these are three questions
so let me
see you know remarks most of the
distribution channels that we got
through the merger with badly uh we are
quite happy with the progress that we've
made uh in those specific partners that
you're talking about the large Banker
partners that we've got in both these uh
relationships with the increase the
share of wallet uh in fact month and
month quarter and quarter even during
this year when we had announced the
transaction to now it has been a
significant increase in uh share of
knowledge
I'll ask gopal to answer the last the
first two questions
yeah so in so far as maybe I will take
the second shot first
in terms of the split of uh Health gdpi
that's for the full year is at about uh
47.82 billion rupees that's for fy23 and
for fy22 that number was 34.87
on the point on the impact of combined
issue nitesh the fact that it's a
commercially viable transaction is why
we have done that and hence to that
extent in terms of it does not have any
uh material impact in so far as the
overall combined ratio is considered
is
this minor positive impact on combined
ratio issue that is the way we should
prepare them that is correct
and then on the health agency I was
talking about health agency gdpi uh for
f by 23 or fi22 so uh is 47.82 billion
is equal Health GDP right agency GDP I
was
5.6 billion
okay okay thank you sir thank you
thank you
this question is from
good evening thank you for taking my
question first uh you know
um on the regulatory chain side the
expensive management now allowable
differentiate between the sahis and the
German shores as far as the health
business is concerned
does that
create some sort of uh you know uneven
things uh like uh uneven uh field uh for
the industry and for you guys uh and
second uh you know I see that your
investment income uh has improved
considerably in Q4 and also if you look
at the Q3 balance sheet versus uh Q4
balance sheet the unrealized gains have
dropped significantly from about 550
crores to about 213 crores
so has there been uh you know
an increase in realized gains in this in
this quarter which is resided in strong
investment income performance
those would be my two questions yeah
I think principally any difference in
our Arbitrage in regulation is not uh
you know something that is uh useful but
having said that I think parties have a
genuine problem in the sense that they
are single Product Company so we can
defray cost across multiple businesses
they can't
when we look at the fact that as a
multi-line company we write different
types of businesses where the cost of
distribution is lower we don't see a big
disadvantage because he's a 35 percent
and we have 30 because we have other
products where the cost of distribution
would be lower
than let's say the health business even
for us the health business would be
higher but we have some advantage in the
other lines of business
uh
on the on the investment side
yeah so uh so if you look at on the uh
Mark to Market side uh the drop in from
554 so let's say 200 crores uh and in
that context the point that you asked us
to whether there is a significant
increase in capital gains for this
quarter visibly let's say quarter four
of last year so there is in that sense
there is not a significant increase if
you look at Q4 of the current years the
capital gains stood at about
1.59 as compared to 1.36 billion which
was the capital gain that one I've seen
in quarter four of last year
uh to your other point on the quarter on
quarter increase in the overall
investment income that is exactly what
we have been talking about to say that
any increase in the interstate regime
obviously occurs well for us given the
fact that as the portfolio starts to get
rebalanced in terms of uh mix of
investment assets which gets invested at
a relatively higher yield you will start
seeing on an incremental quarters maybe
the interest income getting reflected
appropriately so that's the only reason
why you see possibly the increase in you
know investment income otherwise there
is nothing else that is attached to
those numbers just one more point to add
to what gopal said on the investment
side uh I think you know we were
probably
um
we you know we were correcting in
expecting the interested movement in the
market and at this point in time it
seems to be a current decision where we
increase the uh the duration of our
portfolio in the first half of the year
and that's also playing out
uh because of that interested in that
new Koval is talking about we've been
able to take advantage because we
increase the duration of the portfolio
in the first half of the year
right
thanks
thank you
next question is from the line of
subratim datta from Ambit Capital please
go ahead
hello thanks for the opportunity so I
have two questions one on the health
retail Health Science could you talk
about the investment opportunities that
you are looking at going forward also
what these investment opportunities
include an acquisition to drive the
retail health and air channels faster
that's first
secondly
on the yeah
the URL and if I look at this on a or
you know comparative written premium
then that ratio comes out to around 56
percent which are for FY 23 basically it
has been around the 15 59 previously so
it seems like you are cooking more
revenues in fy23 so how should I look at
it if you could give some clarity around
that that would be very helpful
so I think the first two and I'll
request gopal to take the last one
um in terms of health detail as we've
said that this is the area that we want
to uh sustain uh our investment we've
talked about the man part that we've
added during this year and we also said
that we were we wanted to see the
product would again come through uh
clearly the signs are very very positive
if you
if your health business we generally are
performing the market uh having said
that we don't think they've reached the
true level of productivity that we
expect them to eat so there is still
some fraction
on the investment
in terms of improvement in the top line
from that channel that we've added
what we've decided to do is as we go
through the year we would look at how uh
you know where we are reaching with that
investment and we will uh you know
opportunistically add more resources to
see that to ensure that the investment
Focus remains on building the
distribution as we've said over the last
few years our retail Health uh market
share is you know must go there and
average and our plan is to Endeavor it
to over the years you know build it up
so that Focus remains
with regard to acquisition uh you know I
don't want to get into specific
conversation about every you know one
segment or one one specific company I
think we've always been saying that uh
if there are
uh you know viable uh opportunities in
the market where you know an opportunity
which gives us access to our new
distribution or a new business
has also comes with a reasonable price
we are always open but there is nothing
specific that we are looking at at this
point in time
and uh to the third question on the urr
I think uh your arrests we have been
explaining even in the earlier quarters
is purely a function of uh earning the
premiums over the contract period uh and
hence to that extent depending on again
as I was explaining in responsible
earlier calls there are certain lines of
businesses which could possibly depict
in some quarters may be a faster earning
so for example you will see maybe the
crop insurance segment typically
operates for particular seasons uh not
that we are writing a very large
proportion of that particular book but
in terms of any impact that one would
see on the net earned premium you could
see some sexuality attached to it but
otherwise urr is purely a function of
the way the portfolio gets earned over
the contract period and yes if you are
if you had to see last year for example
in fy22 the overall growth was only
about 4.7 percent whereas if you look at
our growth for the current year it's at
about 17 so that's again a factor that
one will have to take into consideration
when you look at earnings of urr over a
period of time there is no there is in
that sense uh nothing one else which is
there as a part of the unexpected
numbers
thank you
next question is from the line of sanket
quora from a vendor spark please go
ahead
yes thank you thank you for the
opportunity uh I wanted to understand uh
what exactly you are going to do with
the crop insurance business in fi 24
loss is what you acquired so so given
given the um rules are around uh and and
if you intend to focus more on retail
business which are objects intensive do
we go a little aggressive on the crop
business in the current year that's
that's the first question
here so let me answer that so are we
going will we go aggressive on
corporations just because of eom
flexibility the answer is no uh we had
said at the beginning of or even last
year last couple of years that you know
post the acquisition we have said that
we will continue to have some exposure
to the crop business now given that
overall Market has improved there are
new schemes which are coming in and the
capacity in the market which is the
total number of players in the market
have reduced but we have been clear that
it could be about four point four to
five percent of our business
that narrative does not change we are
not changing any of those uh objectives
just because of UN
got it and and a given given uh the
reinsurance market as you highlighted as
hardened and probably the commercial
lines potentially could see a lower
profitability in the current year
because of the rules changes uh
um
the Glide path what you
combine gradually
95 despite competitive intensity
increasing in in few profitable lines uh
you still still continue to maintain
that one zero two by 525 will be
achieved or or on could be a deviation
so that's what we said earlier in the
first our you know our objective hasn't
changed uh yes while in commercial lines
the profitability may not be in line
with what we have in the past but at the
same time we've taken a lot of calls
during the year which will play through
in the future is our estimate
expectation the actions that you take
now helps you in the in the next year so
we are uh we are reasonably optimistic
and we will continue to deliver on that
black path that we've talked about when
it comes to commercial lines also you
know I think one of the things that you
which happens on the ground is that
there's a lot of calls that are taken at
a client level profitability so if you
are making a bit more money in in fire
you may be a bit uh relaxed in pricing
your group health or Marine because
you're looking at a workfully
profitability
so if let's say fire profitability comes
down who fell profitability or rather
you know the aggression of the group
health should reduce so those are the
expectations that we've had that we have
and you know some of those changes we've
seen in the group health side as we see
we've not seen an improvement in the num
you know rates as yet but overall we
believe that we will continue to manage
the uh you know commercial line business
profitability the combination May
deteriorate a little bit but that's
something that will make up from the
other lines of business whereas this
year was uh very stressed here in terms
of combination some of those lines
lastly the health investment that we
made
uh you know that that was a cost which I
think gopal has been talking about at
every call as that channel becomes more
productive
we will get some you know benefits there
uh some of the channels that we got from
bharti AXA by the integration you know
there were early days of investment into
including some of the you know large
distribution Partners yeah those are all
beginning to come within reasonable
numbers in terms of combined so all put
together we are reasonably confident
about the numbers
19 percentage I believe it is both for
new and the renewal part uh then then
um can we expect a significant
Improvement in the retail philosophy
show because because 19 Hospital
regulation looks a little unlikely
that's it
so the first part uh
uh uh as usual so far as quarter four uh
Health uh ghi loss issues are concerned
that's at 93.2
and uh so the retail Indemnity loss
ratios for the quarter is about 61 and
if you recollect even in the last
quarter uh when when I think you had
only asked what has been the loss ratios
we had kind of talked about saying that
the group health will possibly end the
year with the Lost ratio of close at
about 95 so if you look at a full year
basis the ghi book loss ratio stands at
about 95. and the retail Indemnity loss
ratio stands at about 64 percent
uh so that's the breakup in so far the
loss numbers are concerned your second
point on uh the increase in the pricing
uh the increase in pricing is with
respect to the renewable book
um it's not that it's on the entire book
that's one has applied the increase in
pricing but having said that yes to some
extent there will be an improvement in
the overall loss experience but at the
same time as you rightly mentioned there
is always an element of Health inflation
that one sees and going ahead in fy24 we
obviously will also have to see what
kind of a business makes that one is
able to source so there are various
factors that would influence the overall
loss number as we have said even in the
past like in general we believe the
retail Health Indemnity books should
kind of operate at a loss ratio range
which would be between 65 to 70 percent
question
next question is from the reign of core
of single from Apex management please go
ahead
yeah hi thanks for taking my question uh
that's just one question from my side uh
so for the investment what can we have
what's the uh average maturity and also
uh what's the difference roughly between
the yield that we are realizing on the
on the investment book right now
excluding capital gains and uh and and
the incremental yield that we can invest
by maintaining the same average duration
thank you
so the duration of the book at the end
of the year fi 23 was 4.99 uh this is
slightly lower duration than what we had
at the end of nine months because you
know in the month of March we had a very
good inflows into the portfolio largely
because uh The Marked numbers from a
business perspective are positive and
also the corporate business some of the
you know premium comes in so that money
obviously was not invested we didn't
have enough time to invest in the long
division one so that's sitting on cash
so hence the deviation of portfolio was
slightly lower than what it was uh as on
nine months so it's about 4.99 roughly
about
all right thank you
thank you
next question is from the line of Niraj
social from UBS Securities please go
ahead
uh what did you know uh our thoughts
[Music]
are we experiencing the deal getting
shorter and is that you are we going to
release the results and that is
considered into our Target combined
ratio
the answer
is as in it's not you know in some
factor in our Target combined ratio we
are still not assuming any change in the
underlying pattern as we spoke last time
you know the what's happening on the
ground kind of Remains the Same we've
had different judgments in different
High courts some judgments in the favor
of insurance industry some judgments not
so fair in favor of Industry so what we
are what we are doing is we are
observing the trends there are certain
months where it seems like it is
accelerating certain months the data is
not very clear
so as we've been saying that you have to
watch this data for some time I think
what we'll have to see is cases that has
got uh reported with beyond the six
month period obviously we are contesting
all of that we will have to see in the
course how that plays through uh but we
are not assuming any benefit though we
remain reasonably hopeful that in the
longer term this will come uh you know
the courts will rule in favor of the
insurance industry because this is a law
of the land but at this point in time we
are not factoring anything in the second
thing that you remember in PP is that
we've not seen a pyth height right and
in PP we assume a certain claim
inflation as a as a norm as a company
and that came in efficient increases
something that we have continued to
assume even for the coming years so uh
so not only are you not taking a benefit
we are also assuming uh inflation in the
pp claims which is what we've been doing
over the years
or any formulations
and the second uh my question is
go optically it's going to be much lower
given the fact that the interns in words
have been there so both quarter last
year also we had a lower Opex on nwp uh
how do we how to should we think about
it uh in absolute amount also is
actually lower so is it sustainable or
do we think that the rendering like you
jump up or it's a fourth quarter
phenomenon uh any color on that will be
helpful
which which elements were you referring
to
on Opex uh wanted to know income
we will given the fact that it has gone
down both absolute and in terms of
percentage percentage I understand it's
little you know work given uh given the
higher the interesting world so might
have been optically
lower but but what are your thoughts on
on the sustainable amount
in terms of absolute numbers
again there as we keep saying uh you
should again look at more the combined
ratios of the overall operations
because different segments again will
exhibit uh break breakdowns of that
combined differently I mean there are
portfolios which could be high on LR but
relatively little lower cost of
acquisition and conversely the other way
around as well so obviously we'll have
to wait and see how the portfolio
buildup takes place in fy24
but as we have said clearly the
objective is we would want to kind of
stay on that glided path of combined
coming down from 104 to 102 and secondly
what we are seeing is obviously
encouraging science is some of the
Investments that we spoke about this
particularly on the retail Health uh
agency franchise those are starting to
play out as you would have seen in let's
say most of the recent months our growth
percentages have been even faster than
even the Standalone Health companies so
clearly those signs are getting
exhibited but having said that we
continue to stay invested in building
that franchise which will again mean
expensing of cost upfront and the
benefit of revenues coming through over
a period of time so a better trajectory
is to look at more the combined issues
rather than looking at just the let's
say expensive Management number on a
standalone basis
just wanted to understand uh
how one should I look at it I mean
so in general if you look at I mean I'm
just giving a slightly broader range I
think if you look at the loss ratios
they have kind of stayed in the range of
between let's say 70 to 75 in that kind
of threshold uh so again as I said
that's again a function of depending on
what segments of business is one able to
see as an uh area of opportunity and
hence I mean very difficult to kind of
tell you as to what could be the last
ratio number that we will be kind of
working with what we are largely
targeting is the combined ratio
threshold to come down 202 over the next
two years period
thank you
next question is from line of question
from Kodak Mahindra please go in
hi uh thanks for taking my question uh
I'm looking at the advanced premium uh
you know figures and uh you know for
last couple of quarters this is actually
not been going up except it's come down
a little bit uh you know over the last
three quarters uh this was despite the
fact that you're actually being going
faster in Moto GP so I'm just curious uh
as to how should we look at this trade
so if you look at some if you look at uh
uh in general I think the relative
growth for us on the overall motor has
been kind of uh slightly lower than the
market as what we have seen from public
data and relatively if you see the
growth on third party a large part of
the third party grows for us again which
is a thought through approach of
increasing the commercial vehicles
portfolio and there obviously the
commercial vehicle portfolio is not an
and two wheelers is where the portfolio
typically has a longer term tenure
commercial vehicle portfolio in the
current context operates with the one
year term and that's primarily the
reason why you possibly do not see in
that sense a significant change in the
overall Advanced premium numbers as and
when obviously we see the market coming
back as what we have seen some early
time on let's say on the private card
side we should definitely possibly get
to see the advanced premium numbers uh
maybe increasing
thank you
sorry to interpretation
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
a last question I will now hand the
conference over to Mr bhargav dance
Gupta for closing comments
oh thank you thank you everyone for
joining the call so late in the evening
uh and look forward to engaging with you
uh over the next few days thank you
again thank you good night
thank you very much
on behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited that concludes
this conference thank you for joining us
you may now disconnect your likes
thank you